fileheap.com 2002-08-09

# FileHeap! - Legal Info

|  | 

Privacy policy

Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of FileHeap!'s network of sites and services, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it.

**Information FileHeap! Gathers and Tracks  
**

FileHeap! gathers three types of information about users: data that users provide through optional, voluntary registrations and in certain contests and sweepstakes; FileHeap! gathers through aggregating tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites and click through on our newsletters. Such information enables us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers better understand the demographics of our audience. Because FileHeap! derives its revenue mainly from advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. The only situation in which FileHeap! divulges information about an individual user to a third party is with certain contests and sweepstakes--and then, only with the user's express consent.

FileHeap! gathers user information in the following processes:

> **Optional Registration**
> 
> FileHeap! sites offer free, voluntary registration to users. By registering, users can enter FileHeap! without having to log on each time; they gain access to the polling area; and they can take advantage of personalization (the ability to select content according to a user-supplied profile).
> 
> During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address, and must answer mandatory survey questions about age, gender, income, Internet connection, zip code, country, employment status, and other employment information.
> 
> During registration the user has the option of supplying a first name, last name, and password hint. In addition, the user can opt to subscribe to various FileHeap! electronic newsletters and to have his or her email address and/or URL appear in postings.
> 
> **Polling**
> 
> FileHeap! sites offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what the FileHeap! audience thinks about important issues. FileHeap! uses a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.
> 
> **Electronic Newsletters**
> 
> FileHeap! offers a free electronic newsletter to users. FileHeap! gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list through the subscription management pages. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration.
> 
> FileHeap! delivers newsletters, marketing and product offerings via email to only registered recipients from our subscription center. The email tracking system recognizes the URL that was clicked, and records some information about you and your computer, such as the email address that you provided to us, the browser, operating system and IP address.
> 
> FileHeap! also uses the feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your system. This allows us to measure and report the click through rate on e-mails delivered and them better determine future content.
> 
> While aggregate counts of click through behavior are provided to advertisers, an advertiser will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. FileHeap! does not target advertising against specific user information. FileHeap! will not provide specific user information to any third party company.
> 
> **Surveys**
> 
> Occasionally FileHeap! conducts user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.
> 
> **Contests and Sweepstakes**
> 
> FileHeap! offers contests and sweepstakes in which we request certain personal information. At a minimum, the required information includes name and email address; in some cases, the user must answer mandatory survey questions about a range of other personal data. The information gathered in the entry form is used to verify the entrant's identity, to send the entrant an email notification that their entry has been received, and to contact winners and/or prize recipients. There are two situations in which FileHeap! will divulge this information to a third party--provided the user gives express consent:
>
>> 1\. A user may expressly choose to receive additional information from the contest sponsor, in which case the user's personally identifiable information is divulged to the advertiser.
>> 
>> 2\. Some of the contests may be hosted on the FileHeap! site but administered by the sponsor; in such cases, the information a user provides is passed on to the third party as long as that user gives express consent.
> 
> Because the rules and terms of each contest can vary, all information about each contest is clearly posted during the event. All contests and sweepstakes are conducted in full accordance with United States federal and state laws.
> 
> **Usage Tracking**
> 
> FileHeap! tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites.
> 
> FileHeap! sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enters, but this tracking is never associated with individual users.
> 
> **Clear GIFs**
> 
> On occasion, FileHeap! uses clear GIFs to track user traffic patterns. FileHeap! does not aggregate or track personally identifiable information when using clear GIFs, only usage patterns.
> 
> **Cookies**
> 
> A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. FileHeap! uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above), when you register as a FileHeap! member, and when you click an ad: 
> 
> Registration: when you register, FileHeap! uses a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We do not store passwords or any personal information about you. We use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track the pages you visit on our site. Cookies also enable you to enter FileHeap! sites as a member without having to log on each time, and to visit member-restricted areas of the sites. We encrypt the user ID for added security.
> 
> Ads: FileHeap!'s advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates.
> 
> **Opt-in Email Newsletters**
> 
> FileHeap! offers free email newsletters to users in association with NetCreations PostMasterDirect, an independent company that creates targeted email newsletters to announce various products and services. When users subscribe to a FileHeap! newsletter, they are given the opportunity to opt in, or join, announcement lists administered by PostMasterDirect. If users choose to opt in for an announcement list, they will receive email newsletters from third parties via PostMasterDirect on topics selected by the users. Users may have their email addresses removed from the opt-in announcement lists at any time by following the instructions printed in the email newsletters.
> 
> **Third-Party Ad Servers**
> 
> Sometimes we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our sites. These third-party advertising companies employ cookie technology to measure ad effectiveness. To do so, these companies may use information about your visits to our sites and other Web sites. Unless you are otherwise notified, these advertising companies do not use names, addresses, email addresses, or telephone numbers, and they do not link any online actions or cookies to an identifiable person. Use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies. If you would like more information about the privacy policies of the third-party advertisers on FileHeap!'s sites, including information on how to opt out of their cookies, check their sites:

**Use of the Information**

FileHeap! uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience in our network of sites, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

As stated above, FileHeap! uses information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, contests, message boards, and auctions. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (daily or weekly, depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. FileHeap! never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers or partners. When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. FileHeap! does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. FileHeap! creates aggregrate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Data submitted through registration for opt-in email announcement newsletters are provided to PostMasterDirect so that it can deliver the announcements requested by users. This information is never shared with third parties, including the third parties that send announcements through PostMasterDirect. PostMasterDirect and FileHeap! may use aggregated data regarding users' responses to the opt-in email announcement newsletters program to improve the service and to provide information to the companies sending the opt-in email announcements and to other advertisers.

**Sharing of the Information**

FileHeap! uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We do not share information about individual users with any third party, except in the case of some contests and sweepstakes--and then, only with a user's express consent. FileHeap! may make registration records and log files available on a confidential basis to third-party auditors and to select measurement and analysis firms.

FileHeap! does not control the practices of our advertisers. If you have questions about how one of our advertisers uses information about you when you click their ad and go to their content, please contact them directly. (FileHeap! will divulge information only as necessary to comply with state and federal laws.)

**Delete/Deactivate Policy**

Users may unsubscribe to any of our electronic newsletters at any time by following the instructions contained at the end of every newsletter.

Currently, FileHeap! does not offer users a means by which to completely delete personal information established at the time of registration for FileHeap!.

|  |
